<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Caelan Hidalgo Schick</title>
    <link>https://caelanhidalgoschick.com/publications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Caelan Hidalgo Schick</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 16:47:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://caelanhidalgoschick.com/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Policy &amp; Advocacy Panel: Current LatinX Affairs in Pennsylvania</title>
      <link>https://caelanhidalgoschick.com/publications/latinxconnect/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caelanhidalgoschick.com/publications/latinxconnect/</guid>
      <description>According to the 2020 U.S. Census, there are more than one million people of Hispanic/Latinx/Latin@ or Latine origin in Pennsylvania. What does that mean to be Hispanic or Latinx in this state? We celebrate Latinx and Hispanic Heritage Month by highlighting our heritage and what we contribute to this country. In the midst of the celebration, we need to reflect upon pressing issues that we face as a community, diversity, education, health, and inclusion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Periods don’t stop for pandemics: An increase in period poverty and inequality in COVID-19</title>
      <link>https://caelanhidalgoschick.com/publications/periodpov-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caelanhidalgoschick.com/publications/periodpov-copy/</guid>
      <description>Stigmatization of menstrual cycles conceals period poverty on a global scale. Period or menstrual poverty is defined as when those who experience monthly cycles do not have their adequate menstrual hygiene management (MHM) needs met. These needs include access to sanitary products, washing facilities, waste management, pain killers, and information about menstruation.1 The COVID-19 pandemic is demonstrating the importance of this understudied dimension of poverty and inequality. Each day during this pandemic, an estimated 800 million women and girls are menstruating worldwide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dark Side of Superfoods: Negative Externalities in Luxury Commodity and Consumption</title>
      <link>https://caelanhidalgoschick.com/publications/sustainability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://caelanhidalgoschick.com/publications/sustainability/</guid>
      <description>The Latin America and the Caribbean Competency Virtual Series is an opportunity for students to learn more about different topics related to this area and connect with the guest speakers outside of the classroom environment. The students will also have the chance of discussing and asking questions regarding the topic of the presentation. The first presentation will be by Caelan Hidalgo Schick, Panoramas Graduate Coordinator and Graduate student in the Graduate School of Public and International Affairs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
